# GIUSEPPE DI PALMA

I'm 26-years old geek from southern Italy(Napoli). I am a developer, cloud enthusiast and master student of computer science at the University of Salerno. I work together with some international independent music magazine (Le Rane, Meeting del mare) as web content manager. Moreover, in my free time I practice juggling, but for now still at a low level.



## **PERSONAL INFO**

Gender:

Male

**Nationality:** 

Italian

Date of birth:

31/07/1994

#### **CONTACT**

- dipalmagiuseppe1@gmail.com
- Via San Giorgio, Somma Vesuviana (NA)
- +39 366 \*\*\* \*\*\*
- https://giuseppedp.page
- github.com/GiuseppeDiPalma
- in linkedin.com/dplmgspp

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Programming skill**

Java Python C/C++ Bash SQL Swift



#### Cloud

Amazon Aws OpenStack Azure



# **LANGUAGE**

Italian (Mother tongue) English (Level B2)



# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

m 09/2019 - Present

Cloud admin, Developer

Omnia Visio

Via dell'Archeologia 54, Aversa(CE)

Design and implementation of cloud infrastructure for disaster recovery. Development of android application. Server and website maintenance.

**1** 02/2019 - 09/2019

**♀** System Management

Cloud administrator

Via G. Porzio 4, Centro Direzionale(NA)

Enterprise cloud management and administration (AWS, Azure).

Server configuration and management for external customers (Enel, MetroMilano). OpenStack cloud deployment, management and maintenance.

## 2014 - Present

Anywhere

Freelance

Website building and management.

## **EDUCATION**

m 09/2019 - Present

Università degli studi di Salerno, (SA)

Master degree student

Computer Scienze, Specialization in Cloud Computing

Grade point average: 29.6, CFU: 69/120 Expected type achievement: 2021

**1** 09/2014 - 08/2018

♥ Università di Napoli "Parthenope", (NA) Bachelor Sc. degree

Computer science

Thesis: Using genetic algorithms to study the dynamics of insect populations.

**1** 09/2017 - 07/2018

• Università di Napoli "Parthenope", (NA) iOS Essential

Approach to the Apple methodology, with the goal of developing a smartphone application in swift.

**6** 06/2016-10/2016

• Ami Training, Brusciano(NA) Hardware Technician

Practical course on repairing computers and computer networks of various complexity.

#### PROJECTS

- Optimisation on hypergraphs: Developing optimisations to increase efficiency. Julia, C++, OpenMP;
- BMC benchmark Generator: Benchmarch generator for lockfree data structures written in C and Python;
- Semantic harmony social network: Design and develop a social network based on the user's interests that exploits a P2P Network. Java, Doker, tomp2p:
- Word Count: Developing a solution for the problem word count for parallel environment built in cluster on AWS cloud. C with MPI;

- Azure cogito storage: Azure-based smart document tagging. SQL, Blob, AI;
- Genetic algorithm: Web application with genetic algorithm(Bechelor thesis) Python, Django, Deap.

All my projects are available on my github page (link here).

#### **INTERESTS**

- I like open source and finding alternatives to software;
- I have developed a few small projects with Raspberry for IOT at home():
- In the past, I have written several articles for online newspapers about technology;
- I also follow the topic of IT security.

## **ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES**

- Managing and publishing a podcast (interviews) during the Covid-19 pandemic.
- Development and management of web content for Radio musica television.
- Social content management for "Meeting del Mare".
- Construction (website), maintenance and collaboration with the newspaper Le Rane.

## MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP SKILLS

- I coordinated a group of 8 people, photographers and videomakers for the production of social content.
- I lead several teams for university projects:
  - Advanced operating systems: 2 people;
  - Databases and database lab: 2 people;
  - Computer networks: 3 people.

# COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

- Good relation skills gained during my experience with Meeting del Mare.
- In my freelance work I talk to my clients and guide them on the right choices for their projects.

#### **Q PERSONAL DATA**

In compliance with the GDPR and Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003,I hereby authorize the recipient of this document to use and process my personal detailsfor the purpose of recruiting and selecting staff and I confirm to be informed of myrights in accordance to art. 7 of the above mentioned Decree. Gen Do Johan



#### Server management

Linux Windows FreeBSD



#### Linux distro

Ubuntu **CentOS** 



#### Version control tool

Git Svn



#### Software & Tools

Docker **Kubernetes** Wordpress



# Next goal

**AWS Solutions Architect Associate** 

#### **HOBBIES**

- Music
- Running
- Juggling
- Books
- Chess

#### **OTHER**

- Available to relocate
- Available to travel